Inventory of the Victoria Schuck papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- South Vietnam Elections File, 1963-1973
  - National Assembly and Constituent Assembly File, 1963-1971
    - "Personnel and Minor Organizational Changes: the National Assembly,", 1967 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    - Vietnamese Assembly primary and winner runs tables, 1968 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - "Bloc Alignments in the Assembly,", undated (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Upper House File, 1967, 1971-1972
    - "Upper House Election Law,", 1967 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - List of Upper House officials, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Lower House File, 1967, 1971
    - "Lower House Election Law,", 1967, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 13)
    - "Lower House Elections,", 1967 (Box-folder 8: 14)
    - Lower House elections results, 1967 October 22 (Box-folder 8: 15)
    - Lower House election winners, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 16)
    - "Lower House Election List of Elected Candidates in Region II,", circa 1967 (Box-folder 8: 17)
    - Lower House Elections data booklet, 1967 October 22 (Box-folder 8: 18)
    - "Lower House Election,", 1971 (Box-folder 8: 19)
    - "Alphabetical List of Representatives-elect,", 1971 (Box-folder 8: 20)
    - "The Lower House Election, 1971-1975 Term,", 1971 August 6 (Box-folder 8: 24)
    - Lower House Election data booklet, 1971 August 6 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - President and Vice President File, 1967, 1970-1971
    File includes documents, laws, and statements primarily about presidential election, and a few documents related to vice presidential election.
    - "Presidential Election Law,", 1967 (Box-folder 8: 23)
    - Vietnam Report VII: The Presidential Election September 3 1967 (Box-folder 9: 26)
    - The Republic of Vietnam's Presidential Election, 1967 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - "Validation Process," for South Vietnamese Presidential Elections, circa 1967 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - "Voter Participation in Presidential Senatorial Election,", 1967 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Document of law of election of president and vice-president, 1967 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - "Supporter of Thieu Named Top Judge,", 1970 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - "Returns of the Presiential Election As Reported to the Interior Ministry,", 1971 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - "Presidential Election Law,", 1971 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - General Duong van Minh statement about presidential election, circa 1971 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - "Supreme Court's decision and returns of the Oct. 3, 1971 presidential and vice presidential election," (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Senate File, 1967, 1970
    - Chart of Senate Election, circa 1967 (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - "Available Information on Senators-Elect in South Viet-Nam,", 1967 (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - "Candidates for Senatorial Elections," memorandum, 1967 (Box-folder 9: 12)
    - Senate Election, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 13)
- Vietnam Government Administration File, 1956, 1964-1972
  The Vietnam Government Administration File includes a Constitution File along with other materials that include documents, charts, maps, and other items related to the government and administration of Vietnam. More specific topics include village government, hamlet government, military government, local government, regional government, among other topics.
  - Constitution File, 1956, 1967-1969
    File includes documents, decrees, news clippings, and other materials related to South Vietnam's constitution.
    - "Constitution of the Republic of Vietnam,", 1956 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - Constitution documents, circa 1967 (Box-folder 7: 15-16)
    - Constitution for Constituent Assembly Telegram, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 17)
    - "Constitution-Making in Vietnam--A Part of 'The Other War'" article by Schuck in the Mount Holyoke Alumnae Quarterly, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 18)
    - Supreme Court decisions, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7: 5, Box-folder 7: 19)
    - Petition, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 20)
    - A Re-Examination of the 1967 Constitution of the Republic of Vietnam, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 21)
    - Untitled book, photocopy, undated (Box-folder 7: 22-23)
    - "The Constitution of Vietnam - An Analysis and Comparison,", undated (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Ordinance No. 57 and related documents, about administration reorganization, 1956, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Village government documents, 1964 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Payments, budgets, allowances, and salaries, 1964-1966, undated (Box-folder 14: 3, Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Decrees primarily from the Ministry of Interior and the Prime Minister's Office, and about land ownership, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Province, Ministry of Interior, regional administration, and U.S. Agency for International Development Regional Office organization charts, 1964-1966, undated (Box-folder 14: 5, Box-folder 17: 10)
  - "The Historical Evolution of the Hamlet in Vietnam,", 1964 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - "Training of Village Admin. Committees, Hamlet Chiefs, and Deputy Hamlet Chiefs,", 1964 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Public administration in Vietnam documents, 1964 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - "Comparative Study of the Village Government in Vietnam, France, and the United States of America,", 1964 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - "The Province Chief and His Role in the [Governments of Vietnam] Structure,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - The Ministry of Interior and the Supreme Council of Civil Service, 1965 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - "General Status of Local Administration,", 1965 (Box-folder 17: 12)
  - "Principal Steps in Obtaining Approval of G.V.N. Budget Estimates from Provincial Level," chart, 1965 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Military zone maps with organization charts for multiple ministries in a packet, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - "Vietnam Provinces and Major Cities" document, 1965 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - Civil service arrete and decree, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - "Government of Vietnam Program of Action,", 1965 (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - Ministry of Interior documents about local administration seminar and local government, 1965-1966, undated (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - Catolog of the National Institute of Administration of the Republic of Vietnam, 1965 (Box-folder 14: 18)
  - "Change in Cabinets of the Republic of Vietnam,", 1966 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - "Currency Regulations,", 1966 (Box-folder 14: 19)
  - "Government and the Countryside," map, undated (Box-folder 14: 27)
  - "Governing Military Deferment for Cadres of All Branches,", 1966 (Box-folder 14: 20)
  - Public Administration Bulletin Vietnam, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 21-22)
  - Address to open the Second Administrative Convention, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 23)
  - "Cabinets of the Republic of Vietnam," chart, 1969 (Box-folder 14: 25)
  - "The Government of Vietnam," chart, 1971 (Map case)
    Formerly in Box/Folder 13: 2
  - Senate Committee list, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 14: 26)
  - Lowlands and Highlands populations data, undated (Box-folder 14: 28)
  - "Government and the Countryside: Political Accomodation and South Vietnam's Communal Groups," essay, undated (Box-folder 14: 29)
  - "Organization and Operation of Local Government,", undated (Box-folder 14: 30)
  - "USIA Stresses Administration Vietnam Policies,", undated (Box-folder 17: 14)
- Vietnam War File, 1965-1977
  The Vietnam War File includes documents, charts, maps, news releases, and other materials related to the Vietnam War. More specifically, topics include Vietcong, U.S. military assistance, Land-to-the-Tiller, and peace, among other topics.
  - "Message from Ambassador Lodge," United States Operations Mission (USOM) notice, 1965 (Box-folder 14: 31)
  - "Report of In-Service Training 1964-1965," (Box-folder 14: 32)
  - "Revolutionary Development in a Pacified Province,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 14: 33)
  - Aggression From the North The Record of North Viet-Nam's Campaign To Conquer South Viet-Nam booklet, circa 1965 (Box-folder 14: 34)
  - "Text of the Convention," about the Armed Forces of the Republic, 1965 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - War news clippings, 1965 (Box-folder 14: 17)
  - Military documents, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - War Cabinet charts, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 17: 7, Map case)
  - Military zones maps, with marginalia, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - "Return to Press Branch File," about Vietcong, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - U.S. President Johnson and Vietnam speech, article, and book excerpt, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Vietcong war cartoons, in Vietnamese with English translations, circa 1966 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Aircraft location graph, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Newsweek clippings, 17 January 1966 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Department of State Bulletin working paper, progress report, and about U.S. participation, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - "Westmoreland on Vietnam, A Conversation with the U.S. Commander,", 1966 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - United States Mission in Vietnam publications about Vietcong and South Vietnam's Communist party, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 11)
  - JUSPAO [Joint United States Public Affairs Office] Vietnam in Profile booklet, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 12)
  - National Foreign Policy Conference for Editors and Broadcasters, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 13)
  - "Reflections on Vietnam," article from The New Yorker, 16 April 1966 (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - "The Faceless Viet Cong,", 1966 (Box-folder 15: 15)
  - Agency for International Development fact sheet, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 16)
  - News releases about war and military, circa 1966 (Box-folder 15: 17)
  - Vietnampress, includes Vietcong details, 1966 July 12 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - "Rural Pacification in South Viet Nam," report from Editorial Research Report, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 18)
  - "The Search for Peace in Vietnam," article in Viet-Nam Information Notes, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 19)
  - "Commission for War Veterans," chart, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 20)
  - "U.S. Military Assistance Command, Vietnam," directory, 1967 (Box-folder 16: 27)
  - "Ky's Candidacy and U.S. Stakes in the Coming Elections," memorandum, 1967 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - "Can a Free Society Fight a Limited War?," article from The New Leader, 1968 October 21 (Box-folder 15: 26)
  - Communist terror in Vietnam articles, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 15: 22)
  - "Address Vietnam Peace Initiatives by President Richard M. Nixon,", 1969 (Box-folder 15: 23)
  - "Vietnamization is steadily giving More Responsibility to ARVN [Army of the Republic of Vietnam]," article from Vietnam Feature Service, 1970 November (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Land-to-the-Tiller decrees, 1970 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Indochina and "New Myths and Old Realities," news articles by Robert F. Turner, photocopies, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - General Duong Van Minh about remembering comrades and Vietnam peace statements, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Land-to-the-Tiller memoranda, 1971 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - "Is it Too Late to End the Vietnam War?," article, 1971 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - "Press List of Correspondents Accredited to [Military Assistance Command, Vietnam],", 1971 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - "Memorandum from Douglas Pike," about a book about the Vietnam War, 1971 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - "Appeal for Vietnam Peace by men of letters of Free Vietnam," document, 1971 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Vietnam Democratic Force booklet, 1971 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - "Letter from Indo-China" from The New Yorker two articles, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 16: 9, Box-folder 16: 20)
  - "For What Do People Fight? The Problem of Loyalty in South Vietnam,", 1972 (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Vietnam Report, numerous issues, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 16: 11-12)
  - North Vietnam dikes articles, 1972 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Vietnam Bulletin, 1972 April 20 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - U.S. foreign relations with Vietnam, Vietnam's army, and the Geneva Accords, among other issues, documents, 1972 (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - " Life, with Henry Kissinger in His Paris 'Battle Station,", 1972 December 12 (Box-folder 16: 16)
  - Vietnamese and Americans in Vietnam, and President Thieu, and other topics, news clippings, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 16: 17)
  - Henry Kissinger documents, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 16: 18)
  - U.S. President Nixon documents, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 16: 19)
  - "A Warning to Hanoi," article from Newsweek, 1973 (Box-folder 17: 9)
  - White House Press, articles for release, about ending the war and joint military commission, 1973 (Box-folder 16: 21)
  - "Letter from Vietnam," article from The New Yorker, 1973 (Box-folder 16: 22)
  - "Ending the Vietnam War: the Impact of War Costs, Public Opinion, and Anti-War Demonstrations on Senate Voting on Vietnam War Bills," paper, 1976 (Box-folder 16: 23)
  - "The Fall of Saigon: A View from Congress," paper, 1977 (Box-folder 16: 24)
  - Posters about Viet Cong, undated (Box-folder 16: 25)
  - "Composition of the Revised War Cabinet of Vietnam," document, undated (Box-folder 16: 26)
  - "The Birth of the Pathet Lao Army," article, undated (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - "Vietnam: Myths and Realities," paper, undated (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - Command troops, and other topics, handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - The War in Viet-Nam 20 Questions and Answers, booklet, undated (Box-folder 17: 5)
- Miscellaneous, 1967, 1970-1972
  These materials include business card and other materials.
  - General, 1967, undated (Box-folder 17: 15)
    Includes Victoria Schuck's business card, and Incoming Declaration form, and a few empty envelopes with no corresponding cards.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1970-1972, undated (Box-folder 17: 16)
    Includes Christmas & new year's cards, a letter to Schuck, and a memorandum to Schuck.
  - Floor plan in unidentified building for unidentified event, undated (Box-folder 7: 13)